Aren't you excited we're going on our honeymoon?
你期待我們要去度蜜月嗎？
Yeah, I am.
我很期待
That's right, get it out of your system while we're alone.
沒錯，要發作就趁現在沒人的時候
-Hey. We came to say goodbye. -Yeah. Have a great honeymoon.
-我們是來道別的 -對，祝你們蜜月玩得愉快
-Thanks. -I better go pack.
-謝謝 -我最好去打包行李
No, I already packed. The only thing I couldn't find, though, was your Speedo.
不，我已經打包了 我只是找不到你的迷你泳褲
Speedo? I don't have a Speedo.
我沒有迷你泳褲
I'm gonna go pack my regular, long bathing suit.
我要去打包 我那不起眼的超長泳褲
Good, you're still here! I wanted to tell you to have a good honeymoon.
很好，你還在 我來祝你有個愉快的蜜月
Thank you!
謝謝
And I also wanted you guys to know that I am telling the father today.
我還要你們知道 今天我會告訴孩子的爸
What? What?
怎麼了？
-We know it's Ross. -How? How do you know?
-我們知道孩子的爸是羅斯 -你怎麼知道的？
It was his sweater. But, oh, my God!
是他的毛衣，但是天啊
I so wanted Ross to know first. But I am so relieved that you guys know!
我好希望羅斯是第一個知道的 但你們知道了，我真的鬆了一口氣
That is so great. And I'm gonna be your baby's aunt!
這真的是太棒了 我是你孩子的姑姑
I know.
我知道
Me too!
我是阿姨
And I'm gonna be an uncle! Come here.
我是叔叔，來吧
-You're all gonna be aunts and uncles. -Yeah, but I'm the only one related by blood.
-你們都會是孩子的姑姑、阿姨跟叔叔 -對，但只有我跟孩子有血緣關係
So now that you all know, you can help me. Give me some advice on how to tell Ross.
現在你們知道了，你們可以幫我 建議我該怎麼跟羅斯說
What were you gonna say?
你打算怎麼說？
I was gonna tell him that I'm gonna have it, and he can be as involved as he wants.
我要告訴他我想留下孩子 他想怎麼做都可以
Well, that sounds good.
聽起來很不錯
Yeah, but, you know, how do I start? I mean, what's the first thing that I say?
對，只是，我該怎麼開口呢？ 我是說我的開場白應該是什麼？
-Okay, great. Thanks. -Hey, good luck.
-好吧，太棒了，謝謝 -祝你好運
Yeah, bye.
對，再見
Hey, what was that all about?
那是怎麼一回事？
Guess there's no harm in telling you now. Rachel and Ross are going to have a baby.
看來現在告訴你也沒關係 瑞秋懷了羅斯的孩子
What?! I didn't even know that..! Why didn't you tell me?
什麼？我完全不知道 你為什麼不告訴我？
Why am I talking like this?
我為什麼會這樣說話？
-I didn't think you could keep it a secret. -What?!
-我覺得你無法保密 -什麼？
What?!
什麼？
I am an excellent secret-keeper. I have kept all our secrets.
我是保密高手 我一直保守著我們所有的秘密
-What secrets? -No, no, Joey.
-什麼秘密？ -不，喬伊
I'm not gonna tell you, because I am an excellent secret-keeper.
我不會告訴你 因為我是保密高手
-You'll tell me later? -You already know.
-待會你會告訴我？ -你已經知道了
The One Where Rachel Tells
本集播出：告知羅斯
rainystar壓制iPod-MP4
It's so romantic to send people off on their honeymoon.
送別人去度蜜月 真的好浪漫
You know, Monica and Chandler are married. Ross and Rachel are having a baby.
摩妮卡跟錢德結婚了 羅斯跟瑞秋就要生寶寶
-Maybe you and I should do something. -All in good time, my love. All in good time.
-或許你跟我也該找些事來做 -你說的對，吾愛
Shoot! I left my guitar in their apartment. Well, you can let me in later, right?
該死，我把吉他放在他們家 你待會能幫我開門吧？
No, I don't have a key. They took mine to give to you.
不，我沒有鑰匙 他們拿走我的鑰匙說是要交給你
-What? They took mine to give to you. -Why would they take away our keys?
-什麼？他們拿走我的說是要交給你 -他們為什麼要拿走我們的鑰匙？
Maybe they don't trust us.
或許他們不信任我們
They let me keep my key the last time they were out of town.
他們上次出城時 讓我保管他們的鑰匙
The time you broke the ketchup bottle and cleaned it with Monica's guest towels?
那次你打破蕃茄醬瓶 拿摩妮卡給客人的毛巾來清理？
-Hey, I washed those. -No, you didn't.
-嘿，我洗了毛巾 -才沒有
Yeah, that didn't sound like me.
對，那聽起來不像我的作風
-What will I do? I really need my guitar. -I have stuff in there too.
-我該怎麼辦？我需要我的吉他 -我也有東西放在他家
-What stuff? -Monica's chicken parm. I'll take care of it.
-什麼東西？ -摩妮卡的奶酪雞，我得把它解決掉
Hey, Mr. Treeger? It's Joey Tribbiani.
崔格先生？我是喬伊崔比亞尼
Listen, I need to get into Monica and Chandler's apartment. It's an emergency!
聽著，我得到摩妮卡跟錢德家 有緊急事件
Gas leak. Oh, and bring garlic bread.
瓦斯漏氣，帶大蒜麵包過來
-Hey, did Monica and Chandler take off yet? -Yeah.
-摩妮卡跟錢德出發了嗎？ -對
Damn. They left without my pass to the Nassau Fossil and Natural History Museum.
該死，他們沒有帶 納索化石與天然歷史博物館的通行證
There goes the honeymoon.
他們的蜜月泡湯了
-Did Rachel find you? -No, why?
-瑞秋找到你了嗎？ -不，怎麼了？
She was looking for you.
她在找你
Well, I guess I'll catch up with her later.
那麼我待會再見她
-She really wanted to talk to you now. -Yeah, it seemed pretty important.
-她真的得馬上跟你談 -對，似乎是有重要的事
Oh, no.
不
What?
什麼？
I think I might know what this is about.
我想我知道她有什麼事
Really?
真的嗎？
Yeah. We promised we weren't gonna tell anybody this, but..
對，我們答應不會告訴任何人 但是…
About a month ago, Rachel and I slept together.
大約一個月前 瑞秋跟我上床
And?
結果呢？
Wow, I thought you'd be a little more shocked.
我以為 你們會大吃一驚
Oh, sorry. And?!
抱歉…結果呢？
Well, we said we'd just do it that one time..
我們說 只做一次…
but now I think she may wanna start things up again.
我想她或許 想要跟我復合
Yeah, I don't think that's what it is.
我想不是那樣的
-Why? What else could it be? -Oh, wow, I don't feel well.
-為什麼？不然會是什麼事？ -我覺得不太舒服
I'm telling you, that's what it is.
我相信就是那麼一回事
No wonder she was looking at me all funny during the wedding.
難怪在婚禮上 她看我的眼神怪怪的
She didn't say anything to you?
她什麼都沒有告訴你們？
-Maybe it's something you ate. -Could be, yeah.
-或許你吃錯東西了 -有可能
-Please, just go and talk to Rachel. -Yeah, I guess I should.
-拜託，去跟瑞秋談一談 -好吧
Man, you know what I have to realize?
你們知道我領悟到什麼事嗎？
Maybe I'm not the type of guy women can have just one night with.
或許我是那種 讓女人一夜難忘的男人
You know, they always seem to want a little bit more.
她們對我 永遠都覺得不滿足
I should remember that.
我應該記得那一點的
Next.
下一位
-They're kissing. Let's just go around them. -Leave them alone. They're in love.
-他們在接吻，我們先過去吧 -別管他們，他們深愛彼此
I'm in love too. But in an orderly fashion.
我也愛你，不過愛得井然有序
Next.
下一位
Hi. Can you do that and walk? Because she said, "Next."
嗨，你們能邊走邊接吻嗎？ 因為她說「下一位」
Sorry, we didn't hear you. We're on our honeymoon.
抱歉，我們沒有聽到 我們要去度蜜月
Let me see what I can do. There are some first-class seats available.
讓我來看一下 頭等艙還有位置
They bumped them up to first class because they're on their honeymoon!
她讓他們升級到頭等艙 因為他們要去度蜜月
-Let's act like we're on our honeymoon. -We are on our honeymoon.
-我們假裝也要去度蜜月 -我們的確是要去度蜜月
Grab my ass.
快摸我屁股
-Next. -Hi. Sorry, I almost didn't hear you.
-下一位 -抱歉，我差點沒聽見
You know, I'm just so in love with my new husband. We're on our honeymoon.
我深愛我的新婚丈夫 我們要去度蜜月
-Congratulations. -Thanks.
-恭喜 -謝謝
Okay, Mr. Bing, you'll be in 25J, and Mrs. Bing, you're in 25K.
好了，賓先生，你在25J 賓太太是25K
We're on our honeymoon, so can you do your little thing and bump us to first class?
我們要去度蜜月 你能讓我們升級到頭等艙嗎？
I'm sorry, all the first-class seats are taken. That couple got the last two.
抱歉，頭等艙客滿了 剛剛那對夫妻拿走最後兩個位置
See? If we'd gone around them like I said, she'd have given us those tickets! Damn it!
看吧？如果你聽我的話插他們的隊 她會給我們頭等艙的位置，該死
25J and K, any chance those aren't together?
25J跟K 會不會剛好不連在一起？
I still can't believe they took away my key. I mean, you trust me with yours.
我還是不敢相信他們拿走我的鑰匙 你都把你的鑰匙交給我保管
Of course I do! And I'm gonna get it back to you..
那當然 我會把它還給你…
just as soon as they're done with it at the key-shining place.
只要清理鑰匙的人 把它擦乾淨了
-What the hell is that? -I don't know.
-那是什麼聲音？ -我不知道
Treeger, what are you doing?
崔格，你在做什麼？
-You said there was a gas leak. -Why not use your key?
-你說有瓦斯漏氣 -你為什麼不用鑰匙開門？
By the time I found it on this thing, the whole place might have exploded.
等我找到他們家的鑰匙 這間公寓可能都炸掉了
If that happens at another building I manage, people will ask questions.
如果我管理的公寓再發生一次爆炸意外 人們會開始問問題
Come on, hurry up!
快一點
Well, we could have done that.
要那麼做我們也會
Look at that! They're going into the first-class lounge.
你看 他們走進頭等艙休息室了
-Do you know what they have in there? -No.
-你知道裡面有什麼嗎？ -不知道
Me neither. We have to get in!
我也不知道，我們得進去才行
-Just act like you belong. -Oh, my God! Oranges!
-裝做你是頭等艙的客人 -天啊，有橘子
-Nice to see you again. -Sir, may I see your tickets, please?
-很高興又跟你見面了 -先生，麻煩出示你的機票
Yes, of course.
沒問題
Would you move your thumb? I can't see the seat number.
麻煩將你的姆指挪開 我看不到座位號碼
That's all right. I have it memorized. It's 1A.
沒關係 我已經背起來了，是1A
-Sir, this isn't a first-class ticket. I'm sorry. -Apology accepted. Excuse us.
-這不是頭等艙的機票，抱歉 -沒關係，對不起
Sir, I'm afraid I'm gonna have to ask you to leave.
先生 恐怕我得請你們離開
Fine.
好吧
Go, go!
快跑
-Hi. -Hi.
-嗨 -嗨
Hi.
嗨
I think there's something that we really need to talk about.
我想我們真的需要 好好地談一談
I think we do. Why don't we go inside.
沒錯，我們先進去吧
-Look, I know why you're here. -You do?
-聽著，我知道你為什麼會來這裡 -真的？
Yeah, and to save you from any embarrassment..
對 為了讓你有點面子…
I think maybe I should talk first.
我想或許應該我先說
-Okay. -Okay?
-好吧 -好嗎？
Ross and Rachel.
羅斯跟瑞秋
Rachel and Ross.
瑞秋跟羅斯
That's been one heck of a seesaw, hasn't it?
那像是在玩蹺蹺板 對吧？
What?
什麼？
I mean, look, that one night we had was fun and certainly passionate.
我是說那晚 我們過得既滿足又盡性
But don't you think it's better if we just stay friends?
但你不覺得 我們還是當朋友比較好嗎？
Seriously, what?
你是說…什麼？
Okay. You know what?
好吧，這樣好了
If you want to, we can do it one more time.
如果你要的話 我們可以再做一次
I mean, I'd be okay with that. In fact, I have some time right now..
我沒有問題 事實上我現在有空…
Okay.
好了
You know what? Can I talk now?
你知道嗎？我可以說話了嗎？
-Oh, sure. -Okay.
-當然可以 -好吧
I'm pregnant.
我懷孕了
Ross?
羅斯
Okay, whenever you're ready.
好吧，我等你準備好再說
And you're the father, by the way. But you got..
對了，你是孩子的爸 但你有…
-Can I get you some water? -I'm good.
-你要喝水嗎？ -我沒事
Ross, there is no pressure on you, okay? I mean, you can be as involved as you want.
羅斯，別覺得有什麼壓力，好嗎？ 你想怎麼做都可以的
Yeah, I..
對，我…
I'm just, I don't know. I don't understand..
我只是不知道… 我不瞭解…
how this happened.
怎麼會發生這種事
-We used a condom. -I know.
-我們有用保險套 -我知道
But you know, condoms only work, like,97 percent of the time.
但保險套的避孕功能 只有百分之九十七
What?
什麼？
What?!
Well, they should put that on the box!
他們應該標示在包裝上
-They do. -No, they don't!
-包裝上有標示 -才沒有
Well, they should put it in huge block letters!
他們應該用又大又粗的字體 標示在包裝上
-Ross, let's just forget about the condoms. -Well, I may as well have!
-羅斯，別管保險套的事 -早知道當時也不用管了
Listen, you know what? I was really freaked out too..
聽著，你知道嗎？ 我發現自己懷孕時…
-when I found out. -Freaked..? Hey, I'm not freaked out.
-也嚇壞了 -嚇壞了？我才沒有
I'm indignant as a consumer!
我是個憤怒的消費者
-You know what? Let's talk later. -No, I wanna talk now.
-你知道嗎？我們待會再談 -不，我想現在談
In fact, I wanna talk..
事實上我想…
to the president of the condom company.
跟保險套公司的 董事長談
Okay, you know what? Maybe I should come back.. Okay.
你知道嗎？ 或許我該待會再來…好吧
Yeah, I'll press one!
好吧，我按一
-I looked everywhere. There's no gas leak. -So then I can heat this up?
-我到處找過，瓦斯沒有漏氣 -我可以熱一下這個嗎？
Anyway, I'll get moving on that new door.
總之我會幫他們 裝扇新門
Great. Listen, could you do us a favor and not tell Chandler and Monica about this?
太棒了，你能幫我們一個忙 別跟錢德和摩妮卡提這件事嗎？
Because, you know, they don't have any kids of their own..
因為他們沒有 自己的孩子…
and this door was like a child to them.
這扇門就像是他們的孩子
Well, I'm gonna have to put on a new lock. They'll find out anyway.
我得裝上新鎖 他們一定會發現的
It's looking like an all-day job. I'm gonna have to cancel my yoga class.
看樣子要干一整天 我得去取消我的瑜伽課
Hey, Ross. Could you tell Jasmine I can't make it to yoga class today?
羅斯，麻煩你告訴茉莉 今天我沒辦法去上瑜伽課
Sure.
沒問題
-Oh, my God! What happened to the door? -So it's noticeable, huh?
-天啊，門是怎麼了？ -很明顯喔？
-Look, is Rachel here? I need to talk to her. -Didn't you two already talk?
-瑞秋在這裡嗎？我得跟她談一談 -你們不是談過了嗎？
Yeah, but..
對，但是…
Okay. Look, you guys know that Rachel and I slept together..
聽著，你們知道 瑞秋跟我上過床…
but there's something else.
但除此之外還有別的
Rachel's pregnant.
瑞秋懷孕了
-Holy mother of God! -Oh, my God, I can't believe that!
-我的老天爺 -天啊，我不敢相信
-With my child. -That is brand-new information!
-她懷了我的孩子 -我是第一次聽到這件事
-You already know, don't you? -Little bit.
-你們已經知道了對不對？ -知道一點
-How you doing? -Okay. I mean, I'll be okay.
-你還好嗎？ -我會沒事的
It's just, I don't think I handled it very well.
我想 我沒有處理好
-What'd you say to her? -Nothing.
-你跟她說了什麼？ -什麼都沒說
But the complaint department at the condom company got an earful.
但我跟保險公司的客服部門 說了很多
-Then when I turned around, she was gone. -Oh, Ross.
-我一轉身才發現她走了 -羅斯
I know. But in my defense, I just found out that condoms are only, like,97% effective.
我知道，但我剛剛才發現 保險套只有百分之九十七的避孕效果
-What? -I gotta go find her.
-什麼？ -我得去找她
Hey. Hold on! Are you serious?
等一下，你是認真的？
So, like,3 percent of the time, they don't even work?
所以有百分之三的機率 它們無法發揮功能？
They should put that on the box!
他們應該在包裝上做標示
-Evidently, they do. -What?!
-他們的確那麼做了 -什麼？
Well, I'll be.
真的咧
-I can't believe we're here. -You've gotta be kidding.
-我不敢相信我們來到這裡了 -開什麼玩笑
What?
什麼？
As a wedding gift to you, the hotel would like to give you the honeymoon suite.
為了慶祝你們結婚 飯店要幫你們升等到蜜月套房
No! You have been screwing us all day!
不，你們破壞了我們一整天
-Who are you? -We're you. Just 10 seconds later!
-你們是誰？ -我們是你們，只是遲了十秒鐘
You already got the first-class tickets, the lounge. We should get free stuff too!
你們已經搶走頭等艙的位置、休息室 我們也應該得到免費招待
You're not the only ones on your honeymoon!
不光是你們 在度蜜月
You can have the suite if you want. We don't care about where we stay.
我們可以把蜜月套房讓給你們 我們不在乎要睡在哪裡
We're here to celebrate our love for each other.
我們來這裡 紀念我們對彼此的愛
We don't have to get free stuff. We just want to be together.
我們不需要免費招待 我們只想在一起
We need the stuff.
我們需要免費招待
Monica, it's Joey. Phoebe and I smell gas coming from your apartment.
摩妮卡，我是喬伊 菲比跟我聞到你家有瓦斯味
-What? Are you serious? Joey smells gas. -What else is new?
-什麼？真的嗎？喬伊聞到瓦斯味 -還有什麼新消息？
-We'd check it out, but you took our keys. -Well, do something. Get in there!
-我們想看一下，但你拿走我們的鑰匙 -快想辦法進去
-How? I guess I could break down your door. -Yeah, do that.
-要怎麼辦呢？我可以把你家大門撞開 -對，就那麼做
-And you won't blame us for any damage? -No.
-你不會怪我們弄壞東西？ -不會
-Are you doing it? I don't hear anything. -Okay, I'll break it down.
-你在撞門了嗎？我沒有聽到聲音 -好吧，我來撞門了
Hi. He's doing it, he's breaking down the door.
嗨，他正在撞門 他要把門撞開了
Okay, we're in.
好了，我們進來了
-Okay, Rachel, are you comfortable? -If I said I was, would you judge me?
-瑞秋，你還舒服嗎？ -如果我很舒服，你會審判我嗎？
The doctor'll be here in a minute to do your sonogram.
醫生馬上過來 幫你照超音波
Okay.
好的
Oh, man, I swear, if they sold these at Pottery Barn..
天啊，我發誓 如果他們在陶瓷店賣這個…
-Hi. -Hi.
-嗨 -嗨
We need to talk.
我們得談一談
Right now? Because I kind of got an alfresco situation going on over here.
現在嗎？ 我現在的姿勢有點不雅
Please, I really.. I want to apologize for the way I acted earlier today.
拜託，我真的…我想 為我剛剛的表現向你道歉
-That's fine. Can you stay up near my head? -What? Oh, yeah, sorry.
-沒關係，麻煩你待在床頭邊 -什麼？抱歉
I went crazy. I was thinking about myself when I should've been thinking about you..
我瘋了，我只想到自己 我應該要想到你的…
-Okay, head, Ross! Head, Ross! -Right.
-沒關係，待在床頭這邊，羅斯 -對
I want you to know that I'm gonna be there through this whole thing. Okay?
我要你知道 我會一直陪在你身邊，好嗎？
The doctor's appointments, the Lamaze classes, baby-proofing the apartment.
來做產檢、上拉梅茲呼吸課 為寶寶裝潢公寓
Although, we can worry about that after we get married.
但我們可以等到婚後 再擔心那些事
-Married? -Well, yeah, I think we should get married.
-婚後？ -對，我想我們應該結婚
Because that's your answer to everything?
那就是你的解決方法嗎？
No. Because that's the right thing to do.
不，那麼做是對的
Yeah, maybe, if you're in love. But Ross, we are not in love, are we?
或許吧，只要我們相愛 羅斯，我們並不相愛，對吧？
No. But still, I mean, you can't possibly do this alone.
對，但是 你不可能一個人這麼做
Excuse me?
你說什麼？
-You can't even eat alone in a restaurant. -What?
-你甚至沒辦法一個人到餐廳吃飯 -什麼？
If you can't eat by yourself, how do you expect to have a baby by yourself?
如果你沒辦法一個人吃飯 你怎麼一個人帶孩子？
-I can too eat by myself! -When have you ever?
-我可以一個人吃飯 -你什麼時候那麼做過？
When certain people leave the table and I am not finished!
當某些同桌的人吃完飯 我還沒有吃完的時候
Well, certain other people take two hours to eat a bowl of soup!
有些人光喝一碗湯 就得花掉兩個小時
Oh, please. You inhale your food.
拜託，你是狼吞虎嚥
I grew up with Monica. If you didn't eat fast, you didn't eat!
我跟摩妮卡一起長大 不吃快一點的話就沒得吃了
Am I interrupting?
我打擾你們了嗎？
No, Dr. Long. Please come in. This is Ross. He is the father.
不，朗格醫生，請進 他是羅斯，孩子的爸爸
But not the husband, because, evidently, she can do this alone.
但我不是她的丈夫 因為顯然她能單獨帶大孩子
Nice to meet you. I'll get started on this.
很高興能見到你，我要開始檢查了
-Why you can't admit you need me? -I need you to stay near my head!
-你為什麼不能承認你需要我？ -我需要你站在床頭這邊
Okay. Everything looks good. Here it is on the screen.
好吧，看起來很正常 銀幕上的劃面是這樣的
Here's your uterus..
這是你的子宮…
and right here is your baby.
寶寶在這裡
Oh, my God.
天啊
There it is. I see it.
它在那裡，我看到了
Congratulations. I'll give you two a minute.
恭喜 我讓你們獨處一下
-Okay. -Thank you.
-好吧 -謝謝
Pretty amazing, huh?
很神奇吧？
I don't see it!
我看不到它
-What? -I can't see it.
-什麼？ -我看不到它
But you just said that you did.
但你說你看到了
I know. I lied. I didn't want her to think I was a terrible mother.
我知道，我說謊 我不希望她認為我是個很糟糕的母親
I can't even see my own baby!
我連自己的寶寶都看不到
Oh, sure. Come here. Sure, you can. Come here. Look, it's right there.
當然，過來，你可以看到的 過來，就在這裡
Oh, it's beautiful.
好漂亮
I see it now.
我看到了
-Do you really? -No, I don't see it!
-真的嗎？ -不，我看不到
Okay. Come on. All right. Okay.
好吧，來吧
You see this tiny thing that looks like a peanut?
你看到那個像花生一樣的 小東西了嗎？
Yeah.
是的
Sweetie, that's it.
甜心，就是那個
That's it?
就是那個？
Well, I saw that.
我看到了
-Thank you. -You're welcome.
-謝謝 -別客氣
Wow, I can't believe that's our baby.
我不敢相信那是我們的孩子
Yeah, that's our baby.
對，那是我們的孩子
Well, they put up the new door.
他們裝了新門
-So it's all locked up and secure? -Yeah. Why?
-門都鎖好了嗎？ -對，怎麼了？
I was trying to figure out how bad I want one of Monica's turkey pot pies.
我想知道我有多想吃 摩妮卡的火雞肉派
-Hi. -Hey.
-嗨 -嘿
-So how was the doctor? -Everything went great.
-醫生怎麼說？ -一切都很順利
-Good. -Hey, show them the picture of your uterus.
-很好 -讓他們看看你子宮的照片
I don't see the baby. Where is it?
我看不到寶寶，它在哪裡？
Oh, no, I know. I couldn't see it either at first. But it's right..
不，我知道，剛開始我也看不到 但它就在…
Ross, I lost it again.
羅斯，我又看不到了